Finding Aid for United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Lake Superior records, 1853-1961
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Lake Superior records 1853-1961
United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Lake Superior.
1 linear foot
852116 Ba 2
Now known as Mackinac Presbytery. Minutes, 1857-1961, roll of presbytery, 1893-1960; treasurer's account book, 1895-1931; histories, 1876 and 1887; correspondence, 1921-1926, concerning Stanton Fund and dissolution of Hessel church; and miscellaneous.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the Presbytery (donor no. 1151 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
A microfilm copy of te presbytery minute, 1857-1922 is availalbe at the library.
The Presbytery of Lake Superior, after reorganization, is now the Presbytery of Mackinac. Its responsibilities are to the United Presbyterian Churches of northern Michigan.
The organizational records include minutes, 1857-1961, roll of presbytery, 1893-1960; treasurer's account book, 1895-1931; histories, 1876 and 1887; correspondence, 1921-1926, concerning Stanton Fund and dissolution of Hessel church; and miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Hessel (Mich.); Presbyterian Church (Hessel, Mich.); United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.--Michigan.; United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Presbytery of Lake Superior.
- Organizational records
  - Minutes, 1857-1961 (Box 1)
    (microfilm copy available of minutes from 1857 to 1922)
    - 1857-1861 (Old School) (Box 1)
    - 1857-1883 (New School) (Box 1)
      (volume no. I)
    - 1883-1892 (Box 1)
      (volume no. II)
    - 1892-1897 (Box 1)
      (volume no. III)
    - 1898-1912 (Box 1)
      (volume no. IV)
    - 1913-1922 (Box 1)
      (volume no. V)
    - 1922-1939 (Box 1)
      (volume no. VI)
    - 1939-1957 (Box 1)
      (volume no. VII)
    - 1957-1961 (Box 1)
      (volume no. VIII)
  - Roll of Presbytery; Churches, etc.
    - 1894-1923 (?) (Box 1)
      (microfilm copy available)
    - 1893-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1960 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Accounts, 1895-1931 (Box 1)
  - Histories, 1867 and 1887 and miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Correspondence concerning Stanton Fund and the dissolution of the Hessel, Michigan, church, 1921-1926. (Box 1)